《越狱》前情回顾
Previously on prison break
欢迎回家
Welcome home,
老大
boss.
妈妈在哪
Where's mommy?
妈妈一会儿就和我们汇合
Mommy is gonna meet us later,okay?
我不是杀人犯
I'm not a murderer.
特伦斯  斯蒂德曼
Terrence steadman,
总统的兄弟
the president's brother.
不是我干的
I didn't do it.
斯蒂德曼  先生  这属于违禁品
Mr. Steadman,it's contraband.
我带着这个是为了保护自己
I brought it to protect myself.
我们就是来保护你的
That's what we're here for.
我可以用支票来买吗 因为我没有...
Can I write a check for the food? 'Cause I don't have...
你好  荷兰德夫人
hello,mrs.Hollander.
泰迪回家了
Teddy's home.
我是帕姆
It's Pam.
发生什么事了
What's going on?
我爱你
I love you.
替我吻一下卡麦隆好吗
Give Cam a kiss for me, okay?
如果你再打这个电话  你就完蛋了
You call this number again, you're a dead man.
比尔你需要我的帮助  而我想要回我的工作
You want my help, Bill, and I want my job back.
你有什么计划
What's your plan?
当他们两个走进囚车里的时候
When those brothers get in the van,
就是他们活在世上最后做的事
it'll be the last thing they ever do.
保罗 克里曼带了一组人
Paul Kellerman has a team
正在往囚车那里赶
ready to move on the caravan
就在阿尔伯克基市的市郊
just outside of Albuquerque.
当他们动手的时候
When it goes down,
一定会有激烈的枪战
there's sure to be lots of bullets flying.
我要你去确保保罗 克里曼  被乱飞的子弹射中
I need you there to make sure Paul Kellerman catches one.
雷纳德总统毁了你们的人生
President Reynolds ruined your life.
她也毁了我的
She ruined my life.
你们想把那贱人拉下台?
You want to take the bitch down,
你们刚刚找到了个内部盟友
you just found your inside man,
但我们现在必须马上走
but it's got to be right now.Let's go!
我知道出去的路
I know the way out!
我需要一队在西面包抄
I want a team flanking west.
派另一队到河边去
Give me another team down by the river.
有人受伤了
Man down!
给我叫一驾救伤直升机  快
Give me a medevac, ASAP!
我是塔格尔警官
Officer Tuggle.
塔格尔警官
Officer Tuggle?
我在找亚历山大 马宏
I'm looking for Alexander Mahone.
我是他的顶头上司
I'm his direct supervisor.
很遗憾的告诉您
Sorry to tell you this, sir,
他被子弹击中了
but your boy's been shot.
你是谁
Who are you?
我以前一直为总统工作
I used to work for the president.
你为什么要帮我们
Why are you helping us?
快趴下  快
Lay down on the floor, now.
联邦特工  让我过去
federal agent. Let me through.
空中支援部队说
Air support is telling us that
看到了你的车一直从
they saw your vehicle traveling
46号公路上下来
alone down route 46.
46号公路是罪犯可能走的一条路
Route 46--possible exit route for the convicts.
我正在追踪他们
I was securing it.
没有别的意思  但我们要检查每一辆车
No offense, sir, but we're searching every vehicle.
是啊  我也没别的意思  但你要让我过去
Well, no offense, you either let me through
或者把你的上司找来
or you get me your supervisor.
这里的路障由我来负责
I'm supervising this roadblock,
克里曼  特工
agent Kellerman.
很抱歉  我希望你能够先下来
I'm sorry, but I need you to get out of the vehicle.
警官  呃
Sergeant, uh, Humphries.
林肯 布伦斯和迈克尔 斯科菲尔德
Burrows and Scofield
在这不到十分钟内已经跑掉了
have been on the loose for less than ten minutes.
也就是说  现在我们要分秒必争
That means, that at this stage, every second is critical.
所以如果你再多耽搁我一秒
So if you detain me for one moment more,
我就要你们都被撤职  你明白我的意思吗
I will have all of your jobs,do you understand me?
走吧  什么
-Go ahead.- What?
让他走吧
Just let him go.
你还没有回答我的问题
you still haven't answered my question.
我为什么要帮你们哥俩
Why am I helping you?
因为敌人的敌人就是我的朋友
Because the enemy of my enemy is my friend.
你说要扳倒总统  意思是你有计划
You say something about taking down the president.I'm gonna assume you have a plan.
我确实有
I do.
那是只大丹狗  我们用它来猎鸟
It was a great dane. We had a bird hound.
过程很平静
It was very peaceful.
嘘 嘘 嘘  前一分钟它还在呼吸  后一分钟  它就断气了
Shh-shh-shh! One minute she was breatng. The next, she wasn't.
转过来
Turn around.
起来
get up!
Get up!
给我一个不打爆你头的理由
Give me one good reason why I shouldn't blow your brains out!
因为我能给你们  唯一能让你们脱罪的东西
Because I can give you the one thing that's gonna set you free.
我知道特伦斯  斯蒂德曼在哪里
I know where Terrence Steadman is.
你怎么知道斯蒂德曼在哪里
how do you know where Steadman is?
因为这一切都是我策划的
Because I arranged this whole thing.
是你策划陷害了我  没错
- You arranged to set me up?- That's right.
是你策划杀死了我身边所有的人
You arranged the killing of all the people I know.
我只是收到命令  然后执行命令
I was given orders, I executed those orders,
而现在我也被当成靶子追杀  和你们一样
and now I have a bull's-eye on my chest,just like you two.
我不相信他
I don't trust him.
如果我真想让你  你早死了
If I wanted you dead, you'd be dead.
你们想继续逃亡  没问题
You guys want to keep running, fine.
你们想洗脱罪名  就上车
You want to be free, get in the car.
我只说最后一次
Last time I'm gonna offer.
伊利诺伊州  福克斯河监狱
Joliet, Illinois Fox River penitentiary
怎么了  菜鸟
What's up, fish?
看来你日子挺难熬嘛
Looks like you're having a tough time of it.
我很好
I'm all right.
我只是好奇
Well, I'm just curious.
你怎么不和其他"前狱警"在一起啊
Why don't you hang out with the rest of the ex-guards that are locked up here?
哦  对了
oh, yeah.
这里没有前狱警
There ain't any.
你就是那独苗
It's just you.
嘿  等等 等等
hey, ho-ho-hold up, hold up.
我想到一个双赢互利的安排
now, I got what's called a mutual beneficial arrangement in my mind.
我会罩着你  确保没人找你麻烦
I'll look out after you,make sure nobody get up in your mix.
你要做的就是下餐饭后  把甜点带给我
And all you got to do is bring me your dessert after the next meal.
简单极了
It's real simple.
我只是想赶快服完刑  不想找任何麻烦
I'm just looking to do my time.I don't want any trouble.
是啊  你有你想要的  我有我想要的
Yeah, there's what you want,and there's what I want.
下顿饭的甜点
Your dessert after the next chow.
给我送过来  明白吗
You bring it to me. You got it?
不  你找错人了
No. Wrong guy.
嘿  住手  犯人
Hey! Break it up, convicts!
我们没事的  头儿  没事
We're good, boss. We're good.
要么给我进贡  要么尝尝更厉害的
you bring me my treats,or else this goes next level.
你听明白了吗
Do you understand?
他问你话呢  小子
He asked you a question, boy.
明白了
Yeah.
我没听到  你呢  我也没听到
I ain't hear him. You hear him?-I ain't hear him.
明白了  好的
Yeah, okay.
看看这多简单啊
See how easy that was?
这对我俩都好
We're gonna be good friends, man.
堪萨斯州
Ness City, Kansas
苏茜  你没什么好害怕的
There's no reason for you to be scared, Susie Q.
因为我已经原谅了你
'Cause you see, I've forgiven you.
反过来你也应该原谅我
And you, in turn, can forgive me
原谅我的轻率
for my indiscretions,
现在看来那段曾经
which are so far in the past,
在我们各自回忆当中 不过是瑕疵而已
they're nothingbut specks in our respective rearviews.
过了这么久
It's been such a long time.
你看起来还是如此美丽
You look lovely.
好吧
Okay.
我们走  现在就走
Let's go, right now.
我们...  我们能远走高飞
We can, we can go away,
共度美好的时光
spend some time together.
我又不是老式的手摇留声机
Listen, I'm not a victrola,
所以请你别这样耍我
so please don't play me like one.
在黑人社区你不会丢下自己的孩子
There's not a white man's chance in Harlem you'd ever leave your children behind.
跟一个白人私奔
leave your children behind.
对不起
I'm sorry.
别担心
Don't fret now.
你来福克斯河看我那次
When you came to Fox River,
你很生气的向我吐口水
and you spat at me
就好像我是一头...狂恶的畜牲
like I was some kind of. . . rabid animal. . .
其实我很高兴
I was happy.
因为这样的动作发自内心
'Cause such a visceral reaction could only come
说明这个女人依然在意
from a woman who still cares.
孩子们是一无所知的
The children don't know anything.
我不愿让他们害怕 所以我从没告诉他们
The children don't know anything.I didn't want to scare them,
关于你的事情 所以求你...
so I never told them about you,so please don'T.
简直太完美了
That is so perfect.
因为你知道么我们现在的情况吗
'Cause you see what we got here now?
我们给自己留下了一条清白的道路
We got ourselves a clean slate.
不是吗
Right?
那么这就是整个阴谋
So,this is the conspiracy,huh?
这些西装革履的人 像一群小男孩那样相互追逐
Bunch of little boys in suits running around,
不惜彼此相互残杀
trying to kill each other.
真是悲哀
It's pathetic.
你比我们预想的要难对付一些
Well,you were a little more formidable than we anticipated.
蠢货  我们不稀罕你的恭维
We don't need compliments out of you,jackass.
是啊  看见了吗
Oh,yes,there it is,
布伦斯吸的人格魅力
the winning burrows personality.
闭上你的嘴  开车
Shut your mouth and drive.
哪怕是陪审团也会被你征服
The one we really knew would win over a jury.
干得漂亮
Good work.
金姆先生
Mr. Kim.
你们那里到底怎么回事儿
What the hell is going on out there?
当时的情况一触即发
Well,it was touch-and-go there for a minute,
不过我把一且都解决好了
but I got everything handled.
马宏中弹了
Mahone's been shot.
是的比尔 我知道  我就在那里
Yes,I know,bill. I was there.
亲眼看见布伦斯开枪
我们失去了一名宝贵的人才  不过...
I was there.We lost a valuable asset,but...
马宏没死
mahone's alive.
那就好  当时看上去很严重
That's good. It looked bad.
布伦斯和斯科菲尔德在哪
布伦斯和斯科菲尔德死了
Burrows and scofield are dead.
尸体在我的SUV车上
And they're in my suv.
我现在就去埋了他们
I'm heading out to bury them right now.
别埋了他们
Don't bury them.
我要眼见为实
I need visual confirmation.
我会给你照片的
I'll get you a photo.
我再说一遍
I'll say it one more time.
别埋了他们
Don't bury them.
比尔你知道 现在我最想听到是什么吗
You know what'll be nice to hear right now,bill?
一句"谢谢你"
A "thank you.”
他们尸体入土之后 我会向你汇报的
I'll report back when they're in the ground.
你把手机开着会被他追踪到的
You leave that on,he'll trace it.
是啊  密勤局的电话无法追踪  谢谢
Yeah,uh,secret service. It's untraceable. Thanks.
宝贝闺女
Hey,baby girl.
怎么
What?
这是怎么了
What's the matter?
妈妈呢
Where's mommy?
哦  别这样
Ah,come on.
我告诉你了  妈妈的朋友有事儿找她
I told you that mommy was helping a friend. All right?
听话好吗  我们马上就会见到她了
Now we're going to see her real soon.
什么时候
When?
宝贝...
Baby...
我们马上就会和妈妈在一起了
we are going to be with your mommy real soon.
我向你保证
I promise you that.
好吗
Okay?
我不信你
I don't believe you.
蒂蒂
Dede! Dede!
是我啊  兄弟
Yo,trey,it's me,man.
怎么了
What's up?
卡赛那边怎么样
Yo,what's going on with kacee?
我正在法院 她过会儿要被传讯
I'm at the courthouse. She's getting arraigned soon.
你能和她说话吗  她还好吧
Okay. Will you talk to her? Is she all right?
她都进了监狱 所以不 她一点都不好
She's in jail! So,no,she's not all right.
这到底是怎么了
What the hell happened?
你这傻瓜  你以为我想事情变成这样
Listen, your stupid ass think I wanted it to go down this way?
我不管  我先挂了  兄弟
Whatever. Man, I gotta go.
她的律师随时会到
Her lawyer's gonna be here any minute.
听着  听着
No. Listen, listen.
我要你告诉卡赛
now look, I want you to tell kacee
所有的事情都推到我身上  明白么
to put it all on me, all right?
她当时被吓坏了  什么也不知道
That she didn't know what to do,she was scared.
明白么  所有的一切
Okay? All that.
我已经告诉她这样做了
Yeah, I already told her to do that.
由我来谈
I'll do the talking.
- 欧文 克拉斯基- 是我
- Owen kravecki? - That's me.
这是本还有非尔
Hey. Ben and phil.
让我们赶快出发
Let's get it going before our wives
别等老婆们发现这次钓鱼之行
figure out this is a fishing trip.
- 你的渔具呢- 我把它们留在了北方
- Where's your gear?- I keep it up north.
好吧
Okay.
航程需要多长时间
How long is the flight?
1小时40分钟
Hour 40.
我们别无选择
We don't have a choice.
很高兴你醒了
glad you're awake.
锁骨回旋套肌
Collarbone rotator cuff.
再偏右六英尺  你就完了
Six inches to the right, you're dead.
是的  他刚醒来
Yeah, he just woke up.
马宏先生
Mr. Mahone.
比尔 金姆
Bill Kim.
你这幸运的家伙
You're a lucky man.
我
Am I?
克里曼完成了你没做到的任务
Kellerman finished the job you couldn't.
但是很遗憾他还活着
But he, unfortunately, is still out there.
他依然是个麻烦
And he's a loose end.
你必须完成属于你的任务
You have to finish what you were supposed to take care of.
好笑么
Something funny?
凯勒的麻烦比你所想到的还要大
keller is more of a loose end than you realize.
他开枪打我
He shot me.
那家伙...
That guy. . .
你一箭双雕  他先把你耍了
you wanted to double-cross screwed you first.
斯科菲尔德和布伦斯...
Scofield and Burrows. . .
很可能还活着
are probably alive,
和克里曼一起跑了
and on the run with Kellerman.
祝你今天好心情  小金
Have a good day, Kimmy.
我们勾销了克里曼
We neutered Kellerman.
他甚至在法定上已经不存在了
He doesn't even officially exist anymore.
他知道一切
He knows everything.
新墨西哥州的官方发来报告
Reports have been coming in from new mexico officials
逃犯迈克尔 斯科菲尔德和林肯 布伦斯
that escaped convicts Michael Scofield and Lincoln Burrows
不知以何手段从转运车当中
have somehow managed to extricate themselves
得以逃身
from a transport van
原计划这辆车将他们送往芝加哥
that was bringing them back to the Chicago area.
根据早先情况报道  这两名罪犯--
According to this early information, the convicts were--
你们太棒了
you're great.
出类拔萃  我对天发誓
Top-notch. I swear to go
你别让自己太激动了  斯蒂德曼先生
don't get yourself work up, Mr. Steadman.
现在我本该找回了自己的生活
I was supposed to have my life back by now.
打高尔夫球
Playing golf. . .
去看电影...
going to movies. . .
和人们在一起 但是就因为你们解决不了
seeing people, but because you guys can't get a handle
一名工程师和一个小混混...
on an engineer and a petty crook. . .
三年多来我就是一只瓶中船
I've been a ship in a bottle for over three years.
这里绝对安全
Perfectly safe here.
但愿如此
I wish.
我和金姆通过话
I just spoke to Kim.
他要你完成任务
He wants you to finish the job.
是吗
Yeah?
那不可能
Well, that's not gonna happen.
这不是请求
This isn't a request.
我也不是在协商
And this isn't a negotiation
让金姆和克里曼去决一胜负吧
Kim and Kellerman can try to kill each other all day long.
我退出了
But I'm out.
你一定是忘了我们对掌握的情况
You must have forgotten how discreet
一直是多么的守口如瓶
we've been with what we know.
把夏尔斯的事告诉全世界的人 你不去我自己去
Go tell the world about shales. In fact I will.
我杀了一个禽兽
I killed a predator,
一个折磨强奸妇女的禽兽
a man who tortured and raped women
我把他埋在了我家后院
and I buried him in my backyard.
我会去服刑的
I'll do the time.
我不在乎  我不干了
I don't care anymore. I'm out.
我说得够清楚了吗?
Is that clear enough for you?
哥们儿
My man.
味道很好
that's delicious.
别走  别走
Hold up, hold up, hold up.
我们有个麻烦
We've got a problem.
一块巧克力饼
There's one brownie.
我们有五个兄弟
There's five of my boys.
你知道你让我陷于什么境地了么
You see the position you put me in?
他们在那里肚子饿得发叫
They gotta stand there with their stomachs growling will
我却在这里享受美味
I savor this delicious treat.
这让我看上去是个十足的混蛋
That makes me look like a real ass.
你想让我变成混蛋是么
Are you trying to make me look like an ass?
你提出这个条件说
You said the deal was
我要给你送上一块点心
I was supposed to bring you one dessert.
没错  婊子  爷现在不高兴了
Yeah, well. . .I'm fickle, bitch.
现在是五块甜点
now it's five desserts.
每一顿饭
Every meal.
你要是办不到...
now, if you can't come up with thaT. . .
也有一些其它的办法
there are other ways
能让我高兴
to making me happy.
这样吧  我身上还有些糖果
Well, I've got some other candy on me
如果你想要的话
if you want some of that.
那就拿来吧  婊子  不错
Well bring it out, bitch. It's all good.
你们谁要糖果
Y'all want some candy?
如果没记错的话 去浪漫时光度假村那天也有我
if memory serves, I was at storytime village that day, too.
但是这些照片里面都没有我
And I'm not in any of these pictures?
我发誓我在那的
I could have sworn I was.
宝贝  我只是在逗你
I'm just teasing, baby.
每个女人烧毁情夫的相片
Every woman has burned the photographs
当她过后就会明白
of her  aramour only to later realize
爱情的火焰在心中的燃烧
her love burns even harder
不知比相片上强烈多少倍
than the flame she used.
求你了
Please!
泰迪
Teddy!
泰迪叔叔
Uncle Teddy!
我的宝贝你最近好么
How's my girl been?
很好
Good.
你还是不知道怎么写"土猪"这个词
You still getting more a's than an aardvark?
我想死你了
Yeah, I missed you!
彼此彼此  饼干头
Oh, same here, shortcake.
没错  我染发了
Yes, i painted my hair.
瞧瞧你自己
Look at you, zack.
你不再是个半大小子了
You are a boy no more.
我过不了多久就得
'm gonna have to
借你刮胡刀了
I lend you my razor soon enough.
你怎么来这儿了呢
What are you doing here?
妈说你在钻井台找了个差事
Mom said you got a job on an oil rigger?
没错  就在海上
That's right, right out in the middle of the ocean.
但那些金属怪物真是危险
But those metallic beasts are dangerous.
把我给咬伤了
Got myself injured.
别别别...
And don't be. . .
怕什么怕  亲爱的
don't be frightened now, sugar.
在杜威 奇森和豪威的金牌律师为我失去的每根
The good lawyers at dewey,cheatham and howe
手指都索赔了100万
got me a million bones for every digit I lost.
500万美元
Five million dollars?
这意味有了这些钞票
Which means with all that cash,
我想做什么都可以
I can do anything I want now.
我最想做的就是
And all I want to do
把我的钱和时间 统统用在
is spend all my money and all my time
你身上
with you.
住宅区是怎么样的
What's the neighborhood like?
根本没区  50英亩方圆就那一座房子
No neighborhood. The house sits on 50 acres.
我们一条路进出吗
We coming out the way we go in?
不  我们走另外一条路
No, there's a back road we take.
-多少警卫-通常都没有
-How many guards?-Usually none.
现在我真的不能告诉你太多
At this point,I really couldn't tell you.
我只要一觉得不对头
The second I feel this thing going bad,
你脑袋就得开花
you get a bullet in the head.
我希望一切都顺利
I expect nothing less.
我每半小时就跟你汇报一次
I will inform you every half hour.
明白
Understood.
今天早上一架私人飞机由欧文 克拉维基授权起飞
Private jet was chartered by owen kravecki this morning.
-目的地哪里-蒙大拿
- Headed where?- Montana.
别让它起飞
Stop it from taking off.
长官  飞机已经降落了 打电话给斯蒂德曼
It's already on the ground, sir.Poor Steadman
如果是我姐打来的  那我要跟她通话
if that's my sister,I would like to speak to her.
喂
yes?
马上照办  长官
Right away, sir.
撤退
Evac.
斯蒂德曼先生
Mr. Steadman,
你有外套吗  我们要离开这里
do you have a jacket?We need to leave.
离开
Leave?
搞什么  不要
What?No.
马上会有特工来把你带去一个安全的地方
Agents will be arriving shortly to take you to a safe house.
我  我遇到什么危险了吗
W-what do I need to be kept safe from?
你有没有外套  先生
Do you have a jacket, sir?
我不想走  我要跟我姐讲话
I don't want to leave.I want to talk to my sister.
我奉命如果必要可以强行带你离开
I've been authorized to use force if necessary.
快照办  你到底要不要带什么东西
now, is there anything you'd like to bring?
我的药
My meds.
跟他一起去
Go with him.
车5分钟后到
Car's here in five minutes.
我不知道
I don't know, Stella.
她还不出来
She won't come out.
谁愿意整天待在个拖车里
Who wants to be up in the trailer all day, huh?
你愿意吗
Would you?
对极  我也不愿意
Exactly, me, neither.
你想烤个派什么的吃吗
You feel like baking a pie or something?
加点樱桃
A little cherry
或是柠檬味儿的
or lemon meringue?
爸
Daddy?
妈妈是不是跟你一样
Is mommy in trouble,
有麻烦了
like you?
宝贝  过来
Sweetheart, come here.
过来
come here.
听我说好吗?
now, you listen to me, okay?
妈妈什么也没做错
Mommy did nothing wrong.
她在帮一个朋友的忙
She's helping out a friend.
知道吗?
Okay?
好了  我去问问妈妈怎么样了好不好
okay, let me go see how mommy's doing, all right?
-我也去  我要跟她说说话-不不不
I want to come. I want to talk to her.-No, no, no.
你乖乖地坐在这里好不
You sit here like a good little girl, okay?
别让爸爸为难
Don't give me that.
喂 事情有转机了
- Hello?- Things are looking up.
正是我想听到的
Ah, that's what I wanted to hear.
哥们儿  赶紧告诉我
Man, kick it down to me.
她的律师看起来是个会办事的人
Her lawyer seems like he knows what he's doing.
他想应该可以降低保释金
He thinks he can get the bail reduced.
不错不错  听着 卡赛出来以后
Good. All right, listen.When kacee gets out
我要你帮我带个信儿给她
I want you to deliver this message for me. Okay?
告诉她
Tell her
我们可以销声匿迹
that we can all get lost.
你要她交保潜逃
You want her to jump bail now?
小子  你最好暗爽你不在我眼皮底下
Boy, you better be glad you ain't in front of my face
不然我肯定掐死你
or I'd have my hands around your neck.
听着  傻帽儿  给我把话说给她听
Listen, punk, just deliver the message.
行啊  那你们打算怎么着 住山顶洞去
Okay, then what y'all gonna do? Go live in a cave?
-我自有打算  行不行-行  我洗耳恭听
I got a plan, all right?All right, well, let's hear it.
在伊拉克的时候
This guy back in my unit
我们部队有个小子
when I was in Iraq.
他原来在阿拉斯加
he used to go up to alaska
鱼苗孵化站工作
and work at these fish hatcheries, man.
那里人工都是付现金 而且也没人问这问那
They pay you cash and nobody asks questions.
阿拉斯加
Alaska?
没错哥们  阿拉斯加
Yeah, alaska, man.
那里没人管你鸟事
They don't bother you up there, man.
你知道我  卡赛和蒂蒂
You know, me, Kacee and Dede,
我们一家又能团圆了
we could be a family again.You feel me?
哥们  你可别搞砸了
Man, you don't quit.
你放心我不会搞砸
You damn straight I don't quit.
我能不能知道我要去哪儿
do I get to know where I'm going?
该你知道的信息都告诉你了
You'll get all the information you need upon arrival.
我们要把斯蒂德曼转移到贝塔处
Yes?-We need to move Steadman to location beta.
我们派车来接他了
We're sending a car to pick him up.
车已经到了  长官
it's already here, sir.
不可能
Couldn't be.
车刚从我这离开
The car just left.
放下武器
Weapons down.
放下
Down!
放下你们的武器
Put your weapons down!
别烦糊涂
Whoa, don't get stupid.
放下武器
Put your weapons down.
放在地上  快
On the ground. now!
特伦斯  你让开 你上车
Terrence, step away. Get in the car.
你死了反而气色不错
You look pretty good for a dead man.
上车 干吗去
Get in the car!Wh-where? Why?
那是谁啊
Who's there?
- 他抓到斯蒂德曼了- 不要让他跑了
It's Kellerman. He's got Steadman.Do not let him escape.
杀了斯蒂德曼  把他们都杀了
Kill Steadman. Kill them all now.
保罗  求你了  别别..
Paul, please, wait. Don't, don't.
上车 别杀我
- Get in!- Don't kill me.
上车
Get in the car!
快走
Let's go
呕吐是麻醉最大的副作用
Vomiting.It's the worst side effect of anesthesia.
这应该是最后一次了
That should be the last of it.
你觉得我都吐干净了
You figure I'm on empty by now?
是啊
Keep that.
亚历克斯  卡梅龙受伤了
Alex, cameron's been hurt.
怎么了
What happened?
车祸  肇始逃逸了
It was a car, a hit-and-run.
他现在住院了
He's in the hospital.
他腿上有两出骨折
His leg is broken in two places.
我搭下班飞机回克罗拉多  好吗
I'll be on the next flight to colorado, okay?
他在动手术呢 我马上就来  坚持住
He's in surgery now.I'll be right there. Just hold on.Just hold on.
他们不让我进去
They won't let me see him.
他们打电话到我班上  我立刻就来了
They call me at work, I come right here
但他们却不让我看看他
and now they won't let me see him.
拜托...
Pam, please just.
我来之前千万别崩溃了
keep it together until I get there.
拜托了  为了我好吗
Please, can you do that for me, okay?
求你快点来
Please hurry.
马宏先生  你这样子上不了飞机
Mr. Mahone, you cannot get on a plane.
你至少得再留院一天
You need to stay at least another day
在观察观察
for observation.
你有枪伤
You've been shot.
马宏先生  冷静
Mr. Mahone, please.
我必须去看我的儿子
I gotta go see my son
马宏先生  我能明白
Mr. Mahone, I understand.
拜托  至少找医生谈一下
Please. At least stay and talk to a doctor.
出租
Taxi! Hey!
你儿子怎么样了
How's your boy?
胫腓双骨粉碎性骨折是够严重的的
Tib-fib fractures are bad.
但是要是生长切面受到影响
But if the growth plate's affected,
问题可就大了
there's a whole host of problems.
你犯了大错
You made a mistake.
我没  你犯了
No, you did.
你觉得你还能像在邮局上班那样
You think you can just quit
想辞就辞
like you work at a post office?
现在你必须
now, you're needed
归队
back in.
去收拾收拾你自己
Go clean up your mess.
也许在克罗拉多的多拉哥的街道上
Maybe there won't be another accident
就不会再有车祸了
on the streets of durango, Colorado.
明白没
Understand?
封锁每条路
Every road shut down,
搜索每一辆车哪怕是
every car stopped and searched.
一帮尼姑参观黄石公园
I don't care if it's a group of nuns touring yellowstone.
她们野营的帐篷也搜个从里到外
Their camper gets turned inside out.
逻辑上讲  每条路
Logistically speaking,every road's
都得花上好一阵子 是蒙大拿
gonna take some time.It's Montana.
不是曼哈顿(不是蒙小拿)
Not Manhattan.
给我干活去
Get it done.
遵命  长官
Yes, sir.
要是我们有个相机
If we get a camera,
给他照张拿着今天报纸的相片放到网上
we can take a picture of him holding a current newspaper.If we put that on-line,
就能证明他还活着
well, that'll prove he's still alive.
只能证明我们找了个
It'll prove that we found a guy
看上去像总统弟弟的人
that looks like kind of like the president's brother.
指纹  牙医纪录
Fingerprints, dental records?
我们把他彻底处理过
We white-washed him.
牙拔了
Pulled his teeth,
指纹烧光了
burned off his fingerprints.
DNA 跟那个我们杀掉
DNA.To compare against the homeless guy we killed
并且放在斯蒂德曼车上的
homeless guy we killed and put in Steadman's car,
流浪汉对比吗?
put in Steadman's car,
但是我们把所有的DNA采样都销毁了
but we destroyed all exterior dna samples,
所以我们什么都没的对比了
so that there'd be nothing to compare them to.
总能找到个人
There's gotta be someone somewhere
出来指认他的
who can identify this man.
这也是为什么我们给他整容了
Which is why we did the surgery.
颧骨抬高了2厘米
Cheek bones raised two centimeters,
耳朵下降了四分支一英寸
ears lowered a quarter of an inch.
没留什么足以辨认的特点给认识他的人
Not so much that someone who knew him wouldn't cognize him,
但是足够让任何依法鉴定
but enough that any forensic comparison
出那张照片是一个
of a photograph
跟他长相相似的人的
of that man would conclude that he is a look-alike.
一个笑话
A hoax.
相信我
Trust me.
我们对这个相当在行
We are very good at what we do.
求你们了放了我吧
Please just let me go.
特伦斯
Terrence,
你把这间屋子里每个人都变成犯人了
you've made every man in this room a prisoner,
包括你自己
including yourself.
现在是让我们自由的时候了
It's time to set us free.
你们做什么都没用了
Nothing you do will work.
他们不会罢手的
They will not let it.
少装可怜了
Cut the victim act, Terrence.
他巴不得一边搜罗
He was more than happy to play along when he was lining
贪污来的纳税人的钱
his pockets with taxpayer money
一边自得其乐
funneled through ecofield.
然后  当面临诉讼的时候
And then, when the indictment is about to fall,
你准备找谁给你擦屁股
who do you come running to for help, Terrence?
现在我们要在这里待上个一两天
now we are gonna stay here for a day or two,
直到他们以为我们已经逃之夭夭...
until they think we're a thousand miles away.
然后我们去华盛顿
and then we're gonna make our way to DC.
好吗
Okay?
这就是计划了
So that's the plan?
我们把他带到一个满是敌人和FBI的地方去
We take him to a city crawling with company and feds?
那些政府特工还在行动呢
And government agents, still in power,
他们一直在内部帮你父亲做事
who've been working from the inside with your father,
他们可以一直埋伏着
people who can get that this pain in the ass
直到他把一切全招了
to safely tell his story, on the record.
我们就直闯龙穴
And we just stroll right into the lion's den then, huh?
并祈祷我们不被发现
Pray we don't get mauled.
我不认为他们会回到蒙大拿
I don't think they're gonna come to montana,
迈克尔 我们就最好去找他们
Scofield, so we're gonna go to them.
不 别碰她
no, leave her alone!
你想干吗
What do you want with her?
我想要...
What I want is.
和她约会
to date her.
我再去弄点玉米花
I'll make us some more popcorn.
亲爱的 要是我们还吃的下
Honey, if any of us could eat any more corn,
那我可真会感到惊...讶了
I'd be a-aized.
注意我刚才怎么读的没 格瑞西
See what I did there, Gracey?
印第安语里玉米就叫做 讶
Indian word for corn is maize
我刚才说惊...讶
and I said "a-maized. "
我不明白  我糊...涂了
I don't get it. I'm corn-fused.
你可真够聪明的
you are smarter than a bee sting.
美国第二位女总统现在正和我们一起看电视呢
Second female president of these United States,right here watching TV with us.
哦
oh
看看我都做了什么
Look what I did.
－亲爱的 没关系的  －不 我去拿块抹布
-Honey, that's all right.-Honey, that's all right.
不用了 我可以...
No, I can.
我以为我们之前的事一笔勾销了
I thought we had wiped the slate clean.
求你了
Please.
我以为过去的就过去了
I thought we had put the past where it belonged.
是的 都过去了
We did.We did put the past where it belonged.
不要...
do not.
不要 对我撒谎
Do not lie to me, woman.
在背叛我之后 在毁掉我们的一切之后
After turncoatin' me to the authorities,after ruinin' everything we had,
在让我如此心碎之后
after breakin' my heart into so many pieces
我无力挽回这些
that I will never be able to find them all,
但你至少可以...
you can at least.
不要当着我的面
do me the favor as to not stand there
对我撒谎
and lie to my face!
妈
Mom?
扎克 你给我坐在沙发上
ack, you get your ass back on that couch.
快带格瑞西走 快走
Get Gracey! Go!
我给了你们机会
I gave y'all a chance.
记住了
Remember that.
打开22号门
Open on 22.
伙计 你一定是疯了
Dude, you're crazy
是不是别人都在这么说
Is that what the other cons are saying?
是的 不错
- Yeah.- Good.
不过你惹了班克斯
But you took it to Banks?
我想没人敢惹那家伙的
I don't think you want to be messing with him, man.
凡是惹我的人
I'll mess with anybody who
我都不会给他好果子吃
tries to punk me out.
嘿 你知道么
Hey, you know
我是在...试试你而已
好吧 那你现在知道结果了吧
Yeah, well, the test results came back.
上铺的床位得让给我了
And top bunk's mine now.
你有什么问题吗?
You got a problem with that?
什么事 斯托勒
Hey, what's up, Stolte?
你惹祸 光头 惹大祸了
You screwed up, Brad, big-time.
不 我只是宣布了一些事情
No, I had a message to send,
我必须这样
and that message got delivered.
你揍的那家伙 班克斯
The guy you schlocked-- Banks--
他和值夜班的警卫有关系
he's got connections with the guards working nights.
也就是说
Word is,
班克斯今晚要把你从里面拖出来
Banks is gonna have you pulled out of your cell tonight.
那你能不能帮我下
Well, can't you do nothing?
我能先警告你下
Yeah, I can warn you,
我现在正在帮你呢
which is what I'm doing.
那 你能否
Well, can't you
跟值夜班的兄弟去说说
talk to some of the guys working nights?
他们值夜班就是因为你让他们值的
They're working nights 'cause you put them on nights.
你之前真应该对他们好点
You should've treated the men better when you were here.
他们不会帮你的 大光头
They ain't gonna do you any favors, Brad.
我对你不错 不是吗
I treated you right, didn't I?
帮帮忙吧 斯拖勒
Come on, Stolte.
帮我一把吧 求你了
Please?
你是对我不错
You did treat me right,
但我现在也无能为力
but there is nothing I can do
只能先通知你下
now except warn you.
小心点吧
Watch your back.
我们可以利用国家冰河公园里巡逻员用的消防通道
we can use the fire roads that the park rangers use in Glacier National Park.
夜间他们不巡逻
They don't patrol them at night.
然后我们从加拿大一直往东
We get up into canada, we head east,
经过纽约
we cut down through new york.
穿过边界不会遇到麻烦吗
The borders won't be a problem.
别告诉我没人会理睬我们
No, nobody will look for us there.
真的很好笑吗 特伦斯
this is.fun for you, Terrence, really?
不 不 这不好笑
fun for you, Terrence, really?
好笑的是当时我和凯若琳在谈论你
What was fun was when Caroline and I would talk about you,
某个男生迷恋她
and the schoolboy crush that you had on her.
还向她求婚
He proposed to her.
你还以为你能成为 第一先生（女总统的丈夫）
you actually thought that you would be the first husband,
奴隶也能当国王啊
the serf who would be king?
那可真有趣啊...
we laughed so hard.
你站那儿看着他们杀了维罗妮卡
you stood there and watched them kill Veronica!
-布伦斯-而你什么都没做
-Burrows!-And you did nothing!
她因你而死
She died because of you!
-林肯-杀了他毫无意义 他没身份记录 杀了也仅是约翰 邓
Burrows, he has no value to us dead.He has no identity.You kill him, you have just a John Doe.
-放下枪-林肯 我们就快成功了
Just put your gun down.Just put your gun down.
Lincoln We fast success.
值得的 他害死那么多人 还毁了我的生活
Was it worth it?Killing those people, ruining my life?
－我能处理的－闭嘴 没用的 林肯 你不应该这样做
Scofield, get a handle on your brother.Shut up. You're not helping. You're not helping.
相信我 这不是你想要的
Linc, you don't want to do this.
相信我
Trust me.
这就是他想要的
This is what you want
你不应该这么做的
You don't want to do this.
好吗
Okay?
相信我
Trust me.
死了这么多人
So many people dead.
他却还活着
And he gets to live.
喂 喂
Hello. Hello.
他们拒绝保释
They denied bail.
什么
What?
由于你 法官不买帐
Judge didn't buy that it was all you.
马上要立案了
逃跑罪
Aiding an escaped con.
她是成年人了 伙计
She's looking at major time, man.
好吧 那...
All right
呃...
uh.
我要你转告她律师...
I want you to tell her lawyer--
行么 你听我说...
all right,you listen to me--
你告诉她律师...
you tell her lawyer.
我爱你
I love you.
和她律师说我会去自首 好么
Tell her lawyer I'll turn myself in, okay?
不 凯西说你快逃吧
No. Kacee said you need to run.
如果你去自首了
If you get busted or turn yourself in,
迪迪就失去你们两个了
Dede won't have either of you.
他们会把她扔进看护所
And they'll just throw her into foster care.
听着 伙计 我要挂电话了
Look, man, I'm gonna hang up this phone right now,
因为我怕说出些让我自己后悔的话
'cause I feel I might say something I regret.
你...
Yo.
你照顾好迪迪
you just take care of Dede.
你们知道吗... 在我小时候
you know that.my daddy wasn't really in the picture
父亲对我影响真的不是很深
much when I was growing up.
所以呢
So as a result,
我真的做不了一个好木匠
I never really learned the art of carpentry.
不过我猜 上帝是个好木匠
But I figure, jesus was a carpenter,
他老爹也没怎么教他
and his daddy wasn't around to teach him,
所以我就自学成才了
so I taught myself.
一直以来 我都非常善于用锤子
Over time, I got to be a pretty good swinger of the hammer.
现在呢 好消息是 我不像我老爹
now, the good news is,unlike my papa
也不像上帝他老爹  我会一直在这陪你们的
and the great almighty,I'm here for good.
别误会
Don't make no mistake about it.
我们会成为一家人...
We will be a family.
死也要在一起
if it kills us.
真甜蜜
So sweet.
车子在前面了
car's out front.
让我们整理下出发吧
Let's get covered up and move out.
这两人好像水火不容
These two are never gonna make it in a car together.
你得看好你兄弟
You're gonna have to keep your brother in check.
你不了解他
You don't know him.
那就从他那把我的枪拿过来
Then get my gun from him.
我们没多少时间了
We don't have time for this.
你仍然认为你掌控着全局 是吧
You still think you're  running the show,don't you?
你仍然认为我没有吗?
You still think I'm not?
是的 请告诉我11频道的新闻热线号码
Yes.I'd like the number  for channel 11 news,please.
你干什么
What are you doing?
这不是我们的计划
This is not the plan.
挂掉
Hang up.
是的 帮我接通  我不会挂
Yes,connect me.I'll hold.
斯科菲尔德 你打到新闻台 他们就会告诉警察
Scofield,you call the news, they call the cops.
是的 帮我接通
Yes,put me through.
挂掉
Hang up.
挂掉电话
Hang up the phone
马上
now!
快挂掉
Hang it up!
11频道新闻热线 乐意效劳
Channel 11 news.Can I help you?
我是迈克尔 斯科菲尔德
This is michael scofield.
我在科特贝克旅馆 11号房
I'm at the cutback motel,room 11.
我要自首
I would like to surrender
大... 光头...
Banks Brad.ley.
brad.ley.
猫儿都回家了 混蛋
warden's gone home,bitch.
老鼠要出来玩玩了
Mice are gonna play.
大... 光头...
Brad.
嘿 大... 光头...
我们来了 小白脸
We are coming,
大... 光头...
Brad.
如果有事发生了 你帮我下 我会记得的
if anything jumps off, you get my back, I won't forget it.
还是算了吧
Why don't you just forget it right now?
你也就是个囚犯 还是众矢之的
You're in this cell,you're top bunk.
到了那里 就看你自己的了
Out there,you're on your own.
大... 光头...
Brad.ley.
想要我是吧 你们这群王八蛋
you want a piece of me,you sons of bitches?
过来抓我啊
Come and get me!
听到没
You hear me?
我不怕你们
I ain't scared of you!
我什么都不怕
I ain't scared of nothing!
哦 大... 光头...
Brad.ley.
大... 光头...
开始祈祷吧
start praying.
喂
yes.
金姆先生...
我想让你知道
I just wanted you to know that
我回来干活了
i'm getting back to work.
很好
Good.
我想你收到我给你的信息了
So I take it you got my message.
是的
Oh,yeah.
非常清楚
Very clear
请等等  好吧
Please,come on.
求你了 求求你了  对不起 特伦斯
Please,come on.I'm sorry,terrence.
太晚了
It's too late.
媒体已经过来了
The press is already on their way.
可以把枪收起来了
You can put the guns away now.
这样不好
This goes wrong,
你们得靠自己了
you guys are on your own.
不 如果 如果... 让我回家吧 求你了
No,if-if-if I go back  home,okay,let me,please.
我回去 特伦斯 我们都不能回去 知道么
I'll go back.Terrence,none of us can,okay?
放松下 保持冷静
So just relax and keep your head.
噢...
Oh
好吧 好吧
okay,okay.
特伦斯 特伦斯
Terrence! Terrence!
特伦斯 我要走
I'm leaving!
特伦斯 我们不能让你那么做 特伦斯
Terrence,we can't let you do that,terrence.
特伦斯 我们只是想让你开口
Terrence,all we need is your mouth.
我会在你膝盖上打两个孔
I will shoot out both your knees right now.
我一直都讨厌你 保罗
I never liked you,paul.
我会毫不犹豫地向你开枪的
I won't hesitate to take your life!
好了
All right. Just.
特伦斯... 听我说
Terrence, listen to me.
听着
Just listen.
特伦斯 就这一次 做件该做的事吧
Terrence, for once in your life, do the right thing.
好吗
All right?
由于你 很多人遭受了不幸
So many people have suffered because of this, because of you.
但当新闻媒体来这的时候
But when the press get here,
你可以告诉他们真相
you can tell the truth.
你可以让这一切结束
You can end this.
我呢 如何结束这一切
Where does it end for me?
耻辱 入狱
Disgrace, life in prison?
你已经在监狱里了 特伦斯
就为了你能安全地待在林子的小木屋里
How many more people have to die
还得死多少人啊
so you can stay locked up in some cabin in the woods?
全结束了
It's over.
好吧
Okay.
对不起
Sorry.
特伦斯 不
Terrence, no!
好了
Okay
我们得走了
We have to go.
去哪
Go where?
我们有斯蒂德曼
We got Steadman.
现在什么都没了
No, we have nothing.
只剩下这个约翰 邓了
All we got is a John Doe.
迈克尔
Michael
迈克尔 我们走吧
Michael. let's go